# Mahmood Athil, Senior Technical Support Engineer

mahmoodathil24@outlook.com | +91 63790 70771 | Chennai, IN

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahmood-athil/ | GitHub: https://github.com/madwayl

**SUMMARY** 

Experienced Senior Technical Support Engineer in IT Corporate Environment. Enthusiastic to work with modern tools for Automation and Productivity, and related technologies. Currently skilled & challenged in Web Development, Infra Technologies and Azure Cloud. Excited to handle opportunities with relevance to Cloud Technologies & DevOps practices.

EDUCATION Dhaanish Ahmed College of Engineering

2015-08-14 — 2019-05-10

Bachelor of Technology - Engineering (Petroleum)

**SKILLS** 

Web Development (Beginner): HTML, CSS, Javascript

Version Control Systems (Beginner): Git, Github

**Scripting** (Intermediate): Bash, Powershell, Python

Server Administration (Beginner): Windows Server 2019, Ubunutu Server, RHEL

IT Insfrastructure Library (Beginner): Service Management, Asset Management,

Operations Management

API Testing (Beginner): Postman, Facebook's Graph API Explorer

**EXPERIENCE** 

**Genpact** | Technical Support (Develooer Support Engineer)

2023-04-05 — Present

Supported Products (Meta's APIs & SDKs) and its Use-Cases. Dogfooding New Featured Releases. And Communicate Feature Requests - Maintaining Weekly Metrics

- Assisted on Troubleshooting Product Issues with L2s/L3s/SWEs & with Account/Partner Managers (Full Time Meta Employees) on updating bug resolution for High Tiered Partners
- Create Custom Test Environments, around SDKs and APIs to Debug Common Bugs Reported via Tickets
- o Document Use-Cases, Bugs, Upcoming Features as Wiki or a Knowledge Base Article
- Promoted as Subject Matter Expert (on a span of 3 months)
- Improved Customer Satisfaction for L1 Supported Tickets thorugh a Green-Belt Project
  Improved Response Rate from 5% to 13% and Overall Customer Satisfaction from 28% to 62%
- Dogfood (Testing & Debug) Upcoming/Beta Application Features Requests
- Work Closely with Meta Partner Managers on attempting to resolve Partner Queries
- Use Microsoft Excel/Google Sheets Formulas for Automating Data Capture (via Dashboards) and Root Cause Analysis for Client Review Meetings
- SQL Queries to export custom data from Log Tables (Scuba)
- Utilized Internal Tools Bots, Project Management Tool For Daily Business-As-Usual Tasks
- Handle Client/Partner Escalations for Missed Resolution, though managing Same-Tier Resolution at around 82%

Hilane Digital | Technical Support Engineer

2022-06-20 — 2023-02-13

Maintained Operations of Significance for the

- Create UI Components in Pure JavaScript + React / Scripts based off JavaScript for Business Use Cases
- Creating Scripts (PowerShell) to automate Manual System Tasks
- Analyzing & Maintain Records of new Hardware & Software Assets
- Maintain Azure AD and Monthly Subscription / Payment Reports

Managed IT Support Operations for Project with Digi Telecommunication (Pvt. Ltd.), Malaysia

- Implemented & Maintained ITIL solutions Resolving Incidents & Service Requests (Maintaining 90% SLAs on First Call without escalations)
- Analyse Requirements and Business Use-cases of Application Integration with Organization's Regular Workflow
- Use SQL Queries for Creating Custom Reports via Izenda Reporting Tool
- Test & Troubleshoot APIs for SMS Management (Twilio) & Chatbot Facilities
- Maintain Application Servers (Windows Server 2012 & Ubunutu Server LTS) Check on recurring errors through application log and ensure 24/7 service & Connection Availability throughout Digi Infrastructure.
- Build & Define process with Infra Teams for further server/network device integration, through monitoring account creation WMI, SSH (for Server) & SNMP Based Monitoring via MIB OIDs (for the Network Devices)
- Create BASH / PowerShell Scripts to troubleshoot monitoring issues

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Customer Satisaction Improvement - Green-Belt Project**

2023-07-15 — 2020-10-10

Green-Belt Project on basis of Genpact's 4D Lean Phases (Define, Diagnose, Design, Deploy)

- Response Rate for CSATs (Improved rate from 6% to 13%)
- Improved CSAT Score (Measured Score from 25% to 62%)
- Reduce possibility of Invalid Customer Satisfaction (Out-of-Scope)
- Improve Effective Communication & Triaging for all Agents

## **Azure Cloud Operations**

2020-11-20 --- 2020-12-03

https://github.com/madwayl/cfs-proj

Part of Tech Mahindra's Cloud Finishing School - Cloud Infra for a Business Use-Case

 Business Use Case to Build & Scale an Exemplary Business for their Online Store & Sales Analysis: on Cloud for their Sales Management: Implementing Azure IaaS + Azure Active Directory (via PowerShell, BASH, Ansible, Terraform)

## **AWARDS**

## Ace - Silver Award

2023-12-20

Genpact

On Handling Major Organizational Events. Coordinating Programs & Managing Volunteering Projects as a Coordinator

## **Bhumi's Changemaker Award**

2019-09-15

Bhumi - NGO

On Handling Major Organizational Events. Coordinating Programs & Managing Volunteering Projects as a Coordinator

## VOLUNTEERING Chapter Coordinator | Bhumi

2018-01-10 - 2019-11-20

https://bhumi.ngo/

Top NGO - promotes whole-school transformations and gives educational opportunities to students from disadvantaged communities.

- Managed Volunteer Teams and enhanced volunteering experience organizing Events & Programs
- Teaching Underprivileged Children from Schools & Orphanages about Computer Science and Information Technology

Organizing Events to Embrace Learning (Math & Computer Science) among Communities
 LANGUAGES Tamil (Native speaker), English (Professional)
 INTERESTS Embedded Technologies [ Internet of Things , 3D-Printing ] , Android & Web Development [ Kotlin , Android Open Source Project , React , Flutter ] , Cloud Operations [ AWS , Azure ]